hello today I have for you an
interesting story of mobile CSRF on the
periscope app that was rewarded twice
let's start with a quick reminder of
what is the CSRA vulnerability the
cross-site request forgery usually
occurs when the victim is locked into
the vulnerable side and in the same
browser opens the attackers web page an
Undertaker's website there is for
example an HTML forum that gets auto
submitted to the vulnerable side and the
victim browser automatically attaches
their cookies to the site then the
request is performed on behalf of the
victim and makes an action that benefits
the attacker some way but how does this
attack work on the mobile applications
it works by abusing deep link which is a
custom URL scheme defined by the
application some applications only used
a custom URL schemes to open the app but
it is possible to have a parameters in
the address and the application may
automatically perform an action after
clicking the link so if you are browsing
the web using the mobile browser and all
of a sudden some applications wants to
be run it means that deep link was used
here in this case of periscope app it
was possible to follow user using a deep
link but after clicking such link there
was no confirmation in the application
and it made it vulnerable to the CSRF
attack so an attacker could prepare such
address with his user ID and embed this
URL on his web site and every time
someone would visit his web site hood
authors have made this link and he would
be followed by a lot of people
immediately so it might seem like a not
a very serious bug especially that after
opening the periscope app the currently
followed user would be visible on the
screen which would make it very easy to
immediately unfollow but
the previous reports we say that Twitter
is a company that cares a lot about such
issues so this is the first report it
was rewarded $1500 in June 2019 and it
was publicly disclosed in February 2020
so after the disclosure of the bug
reported on the Android platform another
hunter tried to reproduce the same issue
in the iOS application and strangely
enough he was successful so he has filed
a report in which he only references the
Android issue and one more thing he has
done is he has prepared a
proof-of-concept using a QR code and
what's even more surprising is the fact
that he was rewarded almost $3,000 which
is almost twice as much as the original
report it is very strange first when you
have a mobile bug on one platform it
usually has a equivalent on the another
platform usually you would assume that
after filing a report
they will verify whether the second
platform is vulnerable or not or at
least ask you to do this how is it
possible that I have forgotten about the
other platform my guess would be that
fiction vulnerability for twitter is a
highly automated process maybe they have
a dreary instance paired with hacker one
and the tickets are created
automatically and when there is a
vulnerability that effects Android it
goes to the team responsible for fixing
Android vulnerabilities and not to the
iOS team however the amount of the
bounty spied remains a mystery to me as
I don't think that the QR code
proof-of-concept was worth doubling up
the 1500 bounty the first reported asked
for explanation of this amount of bounty
the twitter team hasn't responded yet
it's been three weeks if they ever will
I will put their explanation in the
comment section down below
for us the takeaway here is when
reporting a mobile application bug it is
always good to ask a question about the
second platform
maybe the team will want us to validate
the vulnerability on the second platform
that's it for today's video I am very
interested in your stories about
submitting reports affecting the mobile
applications leave them down below in
the comment section if you've enjoyed
the video leave a like and a
subscription and thank you